If you're interested in the distribution of a qualitative variable,
要研究分类变量的分布
your primary visualization of choice will probably be the bar chart.
一般都选条形图
Usually, a bar chart is constructed so that each level of
条形图的 x 轴
the categorical variable has a unique x position while
表示分类变量的各类别
the height of each bar illustrates the frequency or count
每个条形的高度则表示频率
of the number of times a data point took on each categorical value.
即每个类别值数据点的数量统计
For example, let's say we gathered
举个例子 假设我们收集了一些调查数据
some survey data and wanted to count the genders of respondents.
想统计被调查者的性别
This bar chart translate the tabular summary into bar heights.
这个条形图将表格汇总数据转换成不同高度的条形形
You can see that the count of males is halfway between
你可以看到男性人数
the 400 and 500 tick marks and the count of females closer to 600 then 500.
在刻度线 400 到 500 之间 女性人数则在 500 到 600 之间 比较接近 600
To avoid information distortion,
为避免信息失真
the baseline for the plot should start from zero.
图表基线应设为 0
If we plotted our example from my 400 baseline instead,
如果条形图基线为 400
then the bar lengths would apply there to be
那么从条形高度来看
three and a half times more females than males rather than about 28% more.
女性人数就会是男性的 3.5 倍 而不是比男性多 28%
For nominal data, you might want to arrange the bars
处理无序分类变量时 建议按频率高低来排列条形
in order of frequency with the most common on the left.
使频率最高的条形居于左侧
This makes it easy to see which category is the most
这样有利于清楚地看到哪个类别的频率最高
common and how the rest of the categories compare.
并与其它类别进行比较
You should not be inclined to do this with ordinal data.
但如果是有序分类数据 最好不要这么做
The inherent order of the levels will usually be a more important feature to convey.
因为级别之间的固有顺序往往是更重要的信息
It's more important to know if the most common categories are lower
更重要的是高频率的数值属于较高级别还是较低级别
or higher in the spectrum rather than just which label is the most frequent.
而不是哪个级别频率最高
Consider this bar chart a survey responses taken on a five-point scale.
来看这个条形图 表示五种级别的调查结果
The highest bar on the left shows that the mode response was agree.
左边最高的条形表示 回答人数最多的是赞成 (Agree)
However, this hides the fact that when opinions are put in
但条形如此分布实际上隐藏了一个事实
their inherent ordering from strongly disagree to strongly agree,
如果把回答按固有顺序排好 从十分反对到十分赞成
the responses were highly polarized between agreement and disagreement.
我们就会看到 赞成人数和反对人数其实都很多
One common variation that you might see for bar charts is the horizontal bar chart.
另一种常见的条形图是横向条形图
In this variation, the chart has essentially turned 90 degrees clockwise
其实就是把条形图顺时针旋转九十度
such that the Y positions indicate category and the X-linked indicates frequency.
此时 Y 轴表示类别 X 轴表示频率
This does not change what is conveyed by your plot,
虽然传达的信息一样
but it's useful to keep in mind depending on how your data is structured.
但我们可以根据不同的数据类型和结构 选择条形图还是横向条形图
If you have a lot of categories or the category names are long,
比如 如果数据类别太多或类别名太长
then the horizontal orientation can be more
那使用横向条形图
convenient in terms of the space needed to create a readable plot.
能节省空间 且提高图表可读性